

Deming Lin

Ang Mo Kio Street 52 Block 596A #25-321, Singapore 561596

□ (+65) 96583326 | ■ deminglindm@gmail.com | ♠ lindeming.com | 回 deming16 | ☐ lindeming

"Whatever it may be, one hundred percent and then some"

Personal Statement

About Me

Hi Sir/ Ma'am!

I'm a penultimate year Computer Science undergraduate at the National University of Singapore. I have been programming for about 2 years, and I love learning about new technologies and getting my feet wet in projects to try them out. Being able to make an impact and help people brings a lot of joy to me, and my 'one day' dream is to be able to combine both my passion in technologies and in making a positive impact to the society.

Experience

My first work experience with technology is back in the army where I had to troubleshoot various IT problems, mainly network related, in my battalion mostly by myself. Not only did I learnt about basic networking tools, I also picked up the skill of having to research and troubleshoot problems independently.

After picking up important programming and software engineering concepts in college, I was offered a back-end software development role at a local startup company NodeFlair during the summer where I quickly transited into doing full-stack web development role. I was tasked with writing back-end APIs, database queries, implementing websockets, providing parts of the front-end logic and styling the platform. I was also tasked with doing basic devops work, mainly on deploying of web application, backing up of servers and database while troubleshooting any problems that occurs along the way.

Currently, I am continuing my work at NodeFlair on a part-time basis and studying. I am also doing basic freelance technology consulting for a small local business where I give advice on and help out with the maintenance of their website. Outside of work and study, I try to explore new technologies and continue to dabble in personal projects during my free time.

Internship Objectives_

I wish to move beyond just being a developer and thus I hope to be exposed to the entire process of problem solving in the context of a startup, from finding a product market fit to scaling the product for many users.

I also hope to delved deeper beyond basic web technologies. If possible, I would also be more than happy to explore new areas like mobile development, machine learning or even data science.

How I Can Contribute

Firstly, I am able to learn fast under stressful conditions. Thus, I am able to quickly familiarized myself with the existing codebase and learn any new technologies required so that I can start contributing within a short time frame.

Beyond development work, I also have some experience in deploying and managing software projects. I have experience deploying across various platforms, such as Heroku and Amazon Web Services.

Finally, I am self-driven and get along well with people in general. I am confident I can integrate well with any team and work well together with them to push quality products fast.

Deming Lin

Education

National University of Singapore

Singapore

BACHELOR OF COMPUTING (HONOURS) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

July. 2017 - Exp. May. 2021

Course details in Appendix A

Serangoon Junior College

Singapore

SINGAPORE-CAMBRIDGE GENERAL CERTIFICATE OF EDUCATION ADVANCED LEVEL (5 DISTINCTIONS)

Feb. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- ACE@SR Scholar for being in top 1% of the cohort academically with excellent conduct
- Dean's List in 2013 and 2014

Work Experience

NodeFlair Singapore

SOFTWARE ENGINEER May. 2019 - PRESENT

- Tech Stack: HTML/CSS, Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL
- Set up back end API end points for retrieval of necessary data from the front end web application
- Write SQL queries to allow server to retrieve data from Postgres database
- Setting up of websocket connections on both front and back end to allow for a real-time chat system
- · Implemented notification system in the chat system, allowing companies to better reach out to talents

Miiostore Costumes Singapore

FREELANCE TECHNOLOGY CONSULTANT

June, 2019 - PRESENT

- Maintains backend server
- · Maintains frontend wordpress plugins
- · Assist in migration of email service and hosting service

National University of Singapore

Singapore

May. 2019 - July. 2019

Nov. 2015 - Dec. 2016

NUS ORBITAL INSTRUCTOR

- Tech Stack: HTML/CSS, React, Nodejs/Express.js, SQL, Git, Github
- Served as facilitator for Full Stack Web Development and Git workshops
- Debug issues faced by students
- Helped students to better understand concepts in web development
- · Provide tips to students on web development

1st Commando Battalion Singapore

• Provided Office Tech Support as one of in-camp duties

- Resolve any IT related issues in the battalion's offices
- Manages the battalion's IT equipment inventory

Programming Related Projects

Portfolio Website

COMMANDO FIGHTER

TECH STACK: JAVASCRIPT, HTML & CSS, SASS

July. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- A revamp of the original bootstrap portfolio site that I had
- Used BEM CSS architecture with SASS 7 in 1 structure
- Used modern CSS properties like cubic-bezier to familarise with them

CarouShare

TECH STACK: MATERIALIZECSS, HANDLEBARS.JS, NODEJS, POSTGRESQL

Mar. 2019 - Apr. 2019

- · A stuff sharing website where people can list items for loan and bid for items to borrow
- Implemented schema and database for the web app
- Implemented back end API using Express.js and database queries
- Implemented front end UI interaction of the web app

4 Player Pong

TECH STACK: WEBRTC, C, UNITY, JAVASCRIPT, HTML & CSS

Feb. 2019 - Feb 2019

- · Made a multiplayer game where players play using a shared screen while using their mobile devices as a controller
- · Handled the making of the game itself and connecting WebRTC to the WebGL game

ModsUni

TECH STACK: JAVA, JAVAFX, JUNIT

Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2018

- Implemented administration tools to manage the module database
- Implemented GUI for the administration tools
- · Wrote unit and integrated tests for the code base related to the administration tools

AUGUST 3, 2019 DEMING LIN · RÉSUMÉ

Highway

Tech Stack: Unity, C May. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Made a 3D endless runner game during summer
- Players can choose from different avatars and different levels with unique challenges
- Features a leaderboard where top players can compare their scores globally

Video Joiner Shell Script

Tech Stack: Bash Script Dec. 2017 - Dec 2017

- Made a mini bash script to automatically join and convert files downloaded from bilibili
- · Initiated the project to practise bash scripting

Skills_

Programming Java, JavaScript, Ruby

Web Development Node.js, Express.js, React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, HTML5, SASS

Database PostgreSQL, MongoDB **Version Control Tools** Git, GitHub, BitBucket

Devops Linux, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Heroku

Languages English, Chinese

Achievements/Extracurricular Activities

Character and Citizenship Award (Platinum)

Singapore

Jul. 2013 - Jul - 2014

SERANGOON JUNIOR COLLEGE Feb. 2013 - Dec. 2014

- Top 20 in terms of overall performance in academic and non-academic areas
- Outstanding performance and leadership in extracurricular and volunteering activities
- Good display of the school's values
- Maintained excellent conduct and academic performance for all school terms

SRJC Taekwondo Singapore

EXECUTIVE COMMITTEE MEMBER

- NTU Taekwondo Open Poomsae Championships 2014 Oh Jang (Individual) Gold
- NTU Taekwondo Open Poomsae Championships 2014 Oh Jang (Pair) Silver
- NTU Taekwondo Open Poomsae Championships 2014 Oh Jang (Team) Bronze
- National School Games Taekwondo Championships 2013 Il Jang (Team) Silver
- National School Games Taekwondo Championships 2014 Oh Jang (Individual) Silver
 National School Games Taekwondo Championships 2014 Sam Jang (Team) Silver
- National School Games Taekwondo Championships 2014 Sain Jang (Team) Silver
- National School Games Taekwondo Championships 2014 Chil Jang (Team) Silver
- Received Colours Award in both 2013 and 2014

NATIONAL YOUTH ACHIEVEMENT AWARD COUNCIL

National Youth Achievement Award (Bronze)

Singapore

Apr. 2009 - Apr. 2012

Apr. 2011 - Apr. 2012

Outstanding performance and commitment to extracurricular activities

- Outstanding performance as a class environment ambassador
- Consistently help to organised or participated in volunteering activities

National Cadet Corps (Air) Aeromodelling Club

Singapore

HEAD INSTRUCTOR

• Planned and organised weekly trainings for over 30 cadets

- Prepared and conducted lectures for aeromodelling
- Prepared test questions to keep cadets refreshed on aeromodelling fundamentals
- Served as Instructor in RC plane pair flying to help new cadets transit into solo flying
- Awarded the Advanced Aeromodelling Wing in 2011

National Cadet Corps (Air)

Singapore

COMPANY ADMINISTRATIVE SPECIALIST

Apr. 2011 - Apr. 2012

- Manages the nominal roll of over 100 cadets
- · Worked closely with platoon sergeants to keep attendance rate above 90% for all cadets, satisfying a criteria for Best Unit (gold)
- Manages the company's funding and in charge of gathering funds

AUGUST 3, 2019 DEMING LIN · RÉSUMÉ 2

Degree: Bachelor of Computing (Honours) in Computer Science

Cumulative Average Point: 4.06/5.00

Year	Level	Course Description	Grades
Aug - Nov 2017	Year 1/Semester 1	Programming Methodology	B+
		Discrete Structures	В
		Linear Algebra	B+
		Quantitative Reasoning	A-
		English for Academic Purposes	А
Jan - May 2018	Year 1/Semester 2	Advanced Programming Methodology	B+
,	,	Data Structures and Algorithms	B-
		Computer Organisation	A-
		Calculus for Computing	B+
		Innovations in Organisations and Society	S
Aug - Nov 2018	Year 2/Semester 1	Independent Software Development Project (Orbital)	CS
		Effective Communication for Computing Professionals	B+
		Software Engineering	A-
		Introduction to Operating Systems	B+
		Introduction to Computer Networks	В
		Journey of the Innovator	CS
		Asking Questions	CS
Jan - May 2019	Year 2/Semester 2	Database Systems	A-
3an - May 2019	real 2/3emester 2	Design and Analysis of Algorithms	B+
		Public Health in Action	_
			B+
		Probability and Statistics	В
		General Biology	S

NUS Grading Scale: A+ A (5.0); A- (4.5); B+ (4.0); B (3.5); B- (3.0); C+ (2.5); C (2.0); D+ (1.5); D (1.0); F (0)

S = Satisfactory; U = Unsatisfactory

CS = Completed Satisfactorily; CU = Completed Unsatisfactorily

EXE = Exempted; IC = Incomplete; IP = In Progress; W = Withdrawn